They're not just stories anymore.
Scary Stories to Tell in the Dark is a horror, adventure,
mystery film directed by André Øvredal.
Mill Valley, Pennsylvania, Halloween night, 1968.
After playing a joke on a school bully, Stella and her friends decide to sneak into a supposedly haunted house that
once belonged to the powerful Bellows family, unleashing dark forces that they will be unable to control.
Stella Nicholls, played by Zoe Colletti.
Roy Nicholls, played by Dean Norris.
Ramón Morales, played by Michael Garza.
Auggie Hilderbrandt, played by Gabriel Rush.
Chief Turner, played by Gil Bellows.
Ruth Steinberg, played by Natalie Ganzhorn.
Scary Stories to Tell in the Dark is a 2019 supernatural horror film directed by André
Øvredal, based on the book series of the same name by Alvin Schwartz.
The screenplay was adapted by the Hageman Brothers, from a screen story by Guillermo del
Toro (who also produced), as well as Patrick Melton and Marcus Dunstan.
The film, an international co-production of the United States and Canada, stars Zoe Colletti, Michael Garza, Gabriel
Rush, Austin Zajur, Natalie Ganzhorn, Austin Abrams, Dean Norris, Gil Bellows, and Lorraine Toussaint.
In 2013, CBS Films acquired the rights to the book series from 1212
Entertainment, with the intent of producing it as a feature film.
By January 2016, it was announced that del Toro would develop
and potentially direct the project for CBS Films.
Øvredal was later set to direct the film, with del Toro,
Daniel, Brown, and Grave being among the producers.
Principal photography began on August 27, 2018, and
ended on November 1, 2018, in St.
Thomas, Ontario, Canada.
Scary Stories to Tell in the Dark was theatrically released on
August 9, 2019, in the United States by Lionsgate Films.
The film was well received by critics with praise for its depictions of the horror features from its source
material, and went on to gross $105 million at the box office, becoming a financial success.
A sequel is in development.
The film explores themes of small town, based on novel or
book, halloween, haunted house, scarecrow.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.